Guide to the Elisabeth Hansot papers SC1311
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Elisabeth Hansot papers
1954-2005
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Hansot, Elizabeth
SC1311
9 Linear Feet (6 cartons)
Biographical / Historical
Elisabeth Hansot was a Stanford University senior lecturer in Political Science and a Jasper Ridge docent. Along with her partner, David Tyack, Hansot co-authored, “Learning Together A History of Coeducation in American Public Schools.” Hansot died in 2010.
Scope and Contents
The papers include teaching materials, papers, administrative files, as well as personal and professional correspondence.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research use. Audio-visual materials are not available in original format, and must be reformatted to a digital use copy.
Political science -- Study and teaching; Hansot, Elizabeth; Hansot, Elizabeth; Hansot, Elizabeth; Stanford University. Department of Political Science. Faculty
- Papers, Accession ARCH_2017_097
  - Past Annual P.S. Fac. Reports, 1990-1994 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Fac. Repport, 1993-1995 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Lectureship - "Tenure", 1989-1998 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Drafts (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - MTL Criticism, 2004 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Comma Goods Tolle, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Gender Talk Chicago WPSA, 1987 Apr (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Women Admin Talk Santa Clara/Berkeley, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - AERA Talk to School Admin, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - E.H. Talks (1 of 2), 1982/1993 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - E.H. Talks (2 of 2), 1997 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Stan Collab Crow Talk, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Neimann Talk, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - AERA Talks- last version, 1992 Mar 3 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Analysis or Advocacy Talk, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - AAUW/ Crow Talk (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Santa Clara Talk, 1989-1992 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - APSA - Public Talk (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Chicoso toll c - WSPA, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Aera summer critique, 1890-1966 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Seffelloni (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Larry Cuban - Talic + others, 1986-1990 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Chicago/Karnelson (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Conrad - ORT 1-3 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - ORT - Talks Zald, Jacob (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - ORT 3- criticisms (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Speeches 92, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Notes for 1979-1980 speeches (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - EH Resume, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - EH Curriculum Vito (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Retirement, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Jim Elisabeth syllabus + Gores, 1990-1995 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Columbia Univ. courses, 1965-1989 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - 105 proposal, also 324 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - other pol theory, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Reno courses (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Political sciences 1-2, 1978-1980 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Great Issues of Politics, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Stanford Pol. Theory courses (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Stanford, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Poli. Sci - Columbia Divisionexams (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Bibliography - pol. Theory by century (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Plato Republic (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Plato course notes - Arendt, Stern, 1954 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - P.S. (past) bibliographies, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Plato talk (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - SLE (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - PS 151, PS 153 Plato Lecture, 1992-1997 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - PS 151 - Plato lecture statesman, laws (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Statesman - Law (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - PS 151 - Socrates lecture intro (before Apology + Crito) (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - The Sophites notion of law (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Apology (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Sophits (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Crito, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Intro to Plato + 1st lecture PS 15 (U.S. intro) (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Wisdom + heroic republic (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Plato republic (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Ethics Anst. Lectures polisci 151A (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Anst. Pol. (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - A's theory (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - early platonic dialogue, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Proto soros, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Phaedo, Symposium (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - McColl - Iliad, Odyssey (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Plato - Decene Sem. Arendt Sem. (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Wood + Plato, Aristotle (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Plato - intro lecture; Columbia; Joll, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Gorgios (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Stein- Rule of wisdom Law- P's, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Plato - course notes: Deane, Wood + Cumming, Kline (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Pre Sociotics, 1956 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - the end (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Lycur Gus PS12 - Kenyon: 28-80 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - PS 151 syllabus 1993 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - PS 151 exams, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - PS 151 exams 97, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Mechanics - 151, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Kahn - Gr. Pol. Theory (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Greek Pol. Thought gen. Greek to end, 1957 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Greek Political Institutions (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - First of Athenian Constitution to 5th century:Dem., 1982 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Plato papers (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Plato (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Plato sen. Notes (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - Aristotle notes (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - Aristotle - 104 (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - Aristotle - gen. Columbia - 84 (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - Aristotle Papers (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - Utopia Bib Essay, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - Feminist Utopias, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - P.S. 104 Utopias (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - Atwood (Box 2, Folder 51)
  - Fem. Studies reading cyborg Harraw, 1999 Spring (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - Harroway, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 53)
  - Harroway, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 54)
  - Donno Harroway - manifesto Jor Cyborgs + replies (Box 2, Folder 55)
  - PS 442/642 Pub. Personal - E.H., 1980 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - PS 341 - Element: EH, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Elements - PS 341 Intro lecture (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - PS 445/645 Org. theory - EH, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - PS445/645 intro lecture (see notes for 445/645 intro) (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - PS 741 - Seminar in Public per. EH, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Public Personnel Administration volume1, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Public Personnel Administration volume 2, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Theories of Public Administration, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Hope house - bock stuff, 2002 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Political sci. 46 Politicol Bureaucracy Kenyo course list (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Pol sci 45 policy, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - C. T. Adam (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Policy Papers, 1977-1979 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Principles for a graduate school of public policy, 1977 Jan (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Working Paper #53 Policy Analysis is what Information systems are not, 1976 Jul (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - PS 45 David L. Kirp, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Professionalism course (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Panel on professionalism, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - UNR - professionalism syllabus, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - PS 456/656 Professionalism intro lecture (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Professionalism main theme (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Midterm + final, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Stanford art courses, 1957 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - PS 151A (1 of 2), 1999 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - PS 151A (2 of 2), 1999 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - PS. 153 Utopian Political Thought, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Hope House Hansot + Tyack, 2003 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - PS 153A, 1998 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Tina/Simon (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Ethics + Social Justice, 2002 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Women's Rights/ Women's Identities, 2002 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Custom Course Material, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - PS 163 (1 of 3), 1991 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - PS 163 (2 of 3), 1991 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - PS 163 (3 of 3), 1991 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Feminist Studies (1 of 2), 1991 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Feminist Studies (2 of 2), 1991 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Hansot - Comparative Govt., 1961 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Orals / Notes - Hansot (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Hansot / Tyack Marriage, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Email, 1995-2005 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Talks, 1984-1997 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Address Books (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Custom Course Material, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - PS 163 (1 of 3), 1991 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - PS 163 (2 of 3), 1991 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - PS 163 (3 of 3), 1991 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Feminist Studies (1 of 2), 1991 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Feminist Studies (2 of 2), 1991 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Hansot - Comparative Govt., 1961 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Orals / Notes - Hansot (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Hansot / Tyack Marriage, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Email, 1995-2005 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Talks, 1984-1997 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Address Books (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence - Cards (Box 5)
  - Correspondence - Cards (Box 5)
  - Correspondence (Box 6)
  - Correspondence (Box 6)